Barry O'Neill

Princeton, NJ 08540 | barra.oneill@gmail.com | http://meep.nologin.net

Profile

Experienced software developer, specializing in high-availability Java-based web applications. Extensive background in full software development lifecycle, including requirements gathering, design, coding, testing, debug and maintenance.

Technical Skills

Languages/Markup Java, Perl, Shell, Python, HTML, JavaScript DHTML/DOM, XML, CSS

APIs/Frameworks J2EE, Servlets, JSP, Struts, JSF, Android, Spring, JDBC, Hibernate, iText PDF,

LDAP/JNDI, J2ME, XMLBeans, Apache Axis, Oracle Fusion Middleware/ADF,

DHTML/DOM, AJAX, yFiles, Aspose, Eclipse BIRT

Eclipse, Intellij IDEA, JDeveloper, Ant, JUnit, Maven, Selenium, MagicDraw UML, **Tools**

AndroMDA, Mantis, Bugzilla, Cruise Control, Hudson

Web/Appservers Apache, IIS, Tomcat, Websphere, Weblogic, Oracle Application Server

Databases/SQL Oracle, MySQL, MS SQL Server, PostgreSQL

Source Control CVS, Subversion, Perforce, Git

Administration Windows, Linux, Email (Postfix, SLOX), Networks (Cisco Ethernet, ISDN, PIX

Firewall)

Professional History

Verband der Vereine Creditreform, Leinfelden-Echterdingen, Germany

The largest commercial credit rating agency in Germany, with offices in over twenty european countries. My division's product, 'CrefoSystem', offers web and webservice-accessible products to our customers.

Software Engineer, Customer Systems (Dec 2008 - Aug 2011)

- Lead developer for several customer-specific projects with complex workflows, involving J2EE business logic with custom web functionality.
- Collaborated with the software configuration manager on the specification and configuration of our Weblogic, Tomcat, Apache and Oracle DB servers.
- Led the migration of several core CrefoSystem components from Java 1.4 to 1.5, including migration from Weblogic 8 to 10.
- Lead technical role on the "CrefoSystem 2.0" project, using Oracle's Application Developer Framework to deliver Creditreform's newest generation of business information.
- Created a proof-of-concept app (yFiles/AJAX) for visualizing company hierarchy information. This application will be used to replace the legacy applet-based solution, thus vastly simplifying our client's minimum system requirements.
- Lead role on web-based dynamic reporting application, using Eclipse BIRT.
- Developed a Single Sign-On solution for linking sessions across separate application servers.

YouGetItBack, Cork, Ireland

Providing global asset recovery for mobile belongings via the use of physical tagging or software, YouGetItBack now also powers Best Buy's 'Geek Squad Locked & Found' program.

Software Consultant And Contractor (Nov 2006 – Nov 2008)

- Consulted with YGIB on the day-to-day technical affairs of the company's online presence.
- Provided instruction/supervision of junior developers.
- Led the overhaul of the on-line store and tag registration system.
- Designed and prototyped the 'print your own' tag system (iText PDF generation).
- Created the proof-of-concept J2ME implementation of the 'mobile superhero' protection software.
- Oversaw struts/mysql/tomcat/apache/linux configuration, as well as the rollout of upgrades.

Professional History (continued)

TERMINALFOUR, Dublin, Ireland

A leading enterprise content management provider, TERMINALFOUR's product 'Site Manager' is deployed by many large customers with tens of thousands of registered users, supporting hundreds concurrently.

Senior Software Developer (Jun 2002 - Oct 2006)

- Lead developer for of many core modules of the 'Site Manager' product.
- Simplified provisioning for many of our larger customers through the introduction of LDAP integration.
- Introduced proper source control, project structure, and build policies, cutting developer environment setup time in half.
- Designed a more efficient publishing system, resulting in significant savings in publish time.
- Project manager for a year-long project for one of our largest customers, replacing two separate legacy systems with a single web application.
- Designed and developed installation, upgrade and licensing modules which completely changed how our product was delivered to the customer, resulting in huge time savings for both us and the client.
- Supported in-house and customer-based technical staff with the development with our APIs as well as with deployment issues.

Junior Software Developer (Jun 2000 - May 2002)

- Supported several customers with system, configuration and deployment issues.
- Installed and maintained both internal and on-site equipment.
- Designed and developed custom perl and java-based web applications for customers.
- Wrote a significant amount of technical documentation for our intranet.

Ireland On-Line/ESAT Telecom (now: BT Ireland)

Ireland's first commercial internet service provider.

Technical Support Representative (Nov 1998 – May 2000)

- Provided first and second level technical support to both residential and business customers.
- · Trained and supervised new support employees.
- Updated and provided new material for the support intranet.

Education

B.Sc. Computer Applications, Dublin City University, Ireland (2002)

Other Information

Sun Certified Web Component Developer (SCWCD 5) Sun Certified Java Programmer (SCJP 1.4) German Speaker (TELC Zertifikat Deutsch B1)